# Gigi Wood

# Writer, Editor, Web Developer

lowa City, IA gigiwoodic@gmail.com - 319-321-9785

More than 15 years writing, editing and proofreading experience. Award-winning, passionate journalist and web developer with sound judgment who produces superior content for a variety of mediums, including newspapers, magazines, books and web. Strong leadership and managerial expertise, including team building, ability to establish priorities and meet goals.

See more of my work at www.gigiwood.com.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Devlowa Bootcamp**

University of Iowa - Iowa City, IA - June 2014 to Present

#### Responsibilities

Participating in highly-selective, nine-week training program to learn full-stack web development. Hands-on training in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, APIs, databases, servers, Agile development, version control and open source. Actively involved in team projects. Awarded scholarship. Program will be completed Aug. 2, 2014.

#### **Editor**

Corridor Business Journal - Coralville, IA - June 2012 to March 2014

Led editorial content and management of four-person newsroom for eastern lowa's business newspaper, with circulation of 22,000, which has doubled during past five years.

- Coordinated weekly newspaper stories and photos, as well as two daily email updates, company website and specialty magazines. Designed and implemented editorial content for newspapers and magazines, including Entrepreneur 101, Fastest Growing Companies, Largest Privately Held Companies Magazine, Power Book, 2014 Women of Influence 10-Year Anniversary Magazine.
- Managed and planned specialty newspaper editions throughout the year, including the Best of the Corridor, Coolest Places to Work, Forty Under 40, HealthCare Summit and Women of Influence.
- Reviewed budget and strategic planning with administration. Managed staff and coordinated freelance writers and photographers. Oversaw staff hiring and departures. Completed administrative tasks.
- Supervised planning, development and production of new magazines Student Entrepreneurs, Veterans in the Corridor Workplace and Newsmakers 2013. Led major newspaper redesign in 2013.
- Implemented and conducted social media marketing. Developed annual editorial calendar. Researched business topics, wrote stories, shot photos, planned weekly layouts and proofread copy.

## **Senior Writer**

Corridor Business Journal - Coralville, IA - March 2007 to June 2012

Covered business news in 130,000-population Johnson County, home of the University of Iowa and more than \$300 million in commercial redevelopment taking place for 2008 flood recovery. Researched and reported on complex, technical subjects, ranging from aeronautics and manufacturing to technology and healthcare, and translated them into layman's terms for readers.

- Named the 2008 Iowa Small Business Journalist of the Year by the U.S. Small Business Administration.
- Received Gold and Bronze awards from Alliance of Area Business Publications at its annual Editorial Excellence Awards ceremony for coverage of historic flooding in eastern Iowa.

- Took lead in magazine projects, including 40 Under Forty Five-Year Anniversary and Corridor Living.
- Wrote 3,000 words weekly for print newspaper, daily email updates and website. Shot and processed photos weekly. Helped manage website. Contributed to special projects throughout the year.

# **Events & Media Coordinator and Web Master**

Critical Hit Games - Coralville, IA - December 2005 to June 2008

Helped launch startup of a new retail business focused on hobby gaming that attracted customers from across the Midwest. Communicated with major manufacturers, local media and various groups to promote and organize events, advertising and other projects for a small business. Designed and wrote code for website.

# **Book Author, Iowa**

State of Iowa - December 2004 to March 2006

Commissioned to author first-of-its-kind economic development book for the State of Iowa, titled Iowa life | changing. Distributed nationally, 28-chapter book was used as tool to attract companies to relocate to Iowa.

- Researched technical documentation on complex topics, including agriculture, biotechnology, education and healthcare, and adapted into every day, reader-friendly language.
- Traveled more than 10,000 miles in a few months to interview state dignitaries and business executives.
- Publication distributed as a promotional tool to persuade businesses and workers to locate to lowa.

## **Health Reporter, Iowa City**

lowa City Press - September 2002 to December 2004

lowa

- Wrote health and general assignment stories on three local hospitals for daily newspaper. During low staffing, covered various beats, including police, cities, counties, University of Iowa, arts and education.
- Served on Diversity Committee to improve inclusion of minorities in newspaper coverage.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Technical Writing**

Kirkwood Community College March 2014

#### **B.A.** in Journalism

University of Iowa - Iowa City, IA May 2002

# B.A. in English and Psychology

University of Iowa - Iowa City, IA December 1997

LINKS

http://linkedin.com/pub/gigi-wood/3/a07/622

**AWARDS** 

### Gold, Bronze awards

June 2009

Recognized with Gold and Bronze awards from the Alliance of Area Business Publications at its annual Editorial Excellence Awards ceremony for eastern Iowa flood coverage, June 2009.

# Iowa Small Business Journalist of the Year

January 2009

Named 2008 Iowa Small Business Journalist of the Year by the U.S. Small Business Administration

# Jack and Ailene Liechty Scholarship

March 2002

Awarded Jack and Ailene Liechty Scholarship, Spring 2002, University of Iowa School of Journalism.

# Harry S. Bunker Memorial Scholarship

March 2001

Harry S. Bunker Memorial Scholarship, Spring 2001, University of Iowa School of Journalism.

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

**SKILLS** 

Adobe PhotoShop, Agile, Bootstrap, CSS3, Constant Contact, GitHub, Google Development tools, HTML5, InDesign, JavaScript, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Outlook, PhoneGap, Quark Xpress, Ratchet, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), social media, SurveyMonkey and WordPress.